lmax.com 2016-05-07

# LMAX Exchange Privacy Policy

LMAX Exchange
Privacy Policy
Effective date: 3 December 2013

LMAX Privacy Policy
Effective date: 3 December 2013
1.        INTRODUCTION
LMAX Limited trading as LMAX (“we”, “us”, “our”, “ours” and “ourselves” as appropriate) respect your
right to privacy are committed to protecting this. In this policy, ‘personal data’ shall have the same
meaning as ‘personal information’ unless the context requires a different meaning to be given to the
latter term.
This policy (together with our Agreement available from our website, www.LMAX.com (our “Website”)
and any other documents referred to on it and our Cookie Policy) sets out the basis on which any
personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the
following carefully to ensure you understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and
how we will treat it. By visiting our Website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described
in this Privacy Policy.
For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the registered data controller is LMAX Ltd of
Yellow Building, 1A Nicholas Road, London W11 4AN, with registration number 06505809.
2.        INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU
We may collect and process the following data about you:
     Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at
     the time of registering to use our Website, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting
     further services (including, but not limited to, your application, LMAX account number, name, email
     address, home address, telephone number, trading activity and history, commission charged
     (including the portion shared with any third party who introduces you to us (“Introducer”) or is
     engaged in the activities described in 4(iii), (iv), (v), (vi), (vii) and/or (viii)), open and closed trading
     positions, your account balance and other financial information, use of your account and your use of
     our service, Website and facilities). We may automatically capture, store and otherwise process
     information about you even if you abandon the completion of an online application or registration
     form, however, in such circumstances, you will have the right not to allow us to capture, store and
     process your personal data.
     We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by our
     external agents.
     When you report a problem with our Website.
     If you contact us (whether electronically or by post), we may keep a record of that correspondence.
     If you contact us by telephone, we may monitor and/or record your conversations with us and retain
     the recordings for such periods as may be necessary or required by law.
     We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not
     have to respond to them.
                                                                                                                 1

    Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of your orders and the fulfilment of
    such orders.
    With regard to each of your visits to our Website we may automatically collect the following
    information:
            o   technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your
                computer to the Internet, location data, your login information, browser type and version,
                time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform,
                server logs and other communication data;
            o   information about your visit, including, but not limited to, all Uniform Resource Locators
                (URL) clickstream analysis information (which includes collecting, analysing and reporting
                aggregate data about which pages you visit and in what order, which site you have visited
                our Website from and which site you go to after leaving our Website (including applicable
                dates and times)); traffic data; products you viewed or searched for; page response times;
                download errors; length of visits to certain pages; page interaction information (such as
                scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs); and methods used to browse away from the page;
                and
            o   any phone number used to call our customer service number.
    When working closely with third parties (including, but not limited to, business partners, Introducers,
    agents and sub-contractors in technical, administration, support, payment and delivery services,
    advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers) we may exchange
    information about you with them.
    We may obtain information about you from third parties for the purposes of our compliance with anti-
    money laundering, anti-fraud and customer due diligence checks, such as credit reference agencies
    and fraud prevention agencies.
3.      COOKIES
Our Website uses cookies to enable you to use the Website, the online services we offer and the
materials on the Website. Cookies are also used to distinguish you from other users of our Website.
This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Website and also allows us to
improve our Website. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we
use them see our Cookie Policy.
4.      WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the
European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who
work for us, one of our suppliers, Introducers, business partners, agents or sub-contractors. Such staff
maybe engaged in, among other things; (i) the fulfilment of your order; (ii) the processing of your
payment details; (iii) the provision of administration and support services in respect of your customer
account with us; (iv) communicating with you about your account and your account functionality and
tools; (v) marketing and/or promoting services to you; (vi) other administration and support services; (vii)
marketing; and/or (viii) other services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer,
                                                                                                           2

storing and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated
securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our
secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where you have chosen (or where we
have given you) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Website, you are
responsible for keeping this password confidential. You should change your password on a regular basis
and not share it with anyone. This will help to reduce the risk of unauthorised access to or use of your
account. We strongly recommend that you disable any automatic password memory in your browser
prior to using the Website and that you run appropriate anti-spyware, firewall and virus protection on
your computer on a regular basis. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not
completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the
security of your data transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have
received your information, we will use appropriate technical and organisational measures to try to
prevent unauthorised access or other unlawful processing of your information and against accidental
loss or destruction of, or damage to, your information.
5.       USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION
We use information held about you in the following ways:
     To ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for
     your computer.
     To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may
     interest you.
     To provide you with information, products or services of third parties that where you have consented
     to be contacted for such purposes
     To carry out our obligations arising from any agreement entered into between you and us.
     To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
     To notify you about changes to our service.
We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with
information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you
about these goods and services by e-mail, post, SMS message or telephone.
If you are a customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail, SMS, post and/or telephone)
with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to
you.
If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing
purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the application
form). Alternatively you can contact us by email, telephone or post to inform us that you no longer wish
to receive marketing communications. If you unsubscribe to marketing communications, you will still
continue to receive operational communications from us that we deem necessary for the operation of
your account.
                                                                                                            3

We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers or partners who provide
content to our Website, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users. We may
also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to. We
may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our
advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience. For the avoidance of
doubt, Introducers and other third parties which are listed in the ninth bullet point of Section 2 above
shall not be deemed to be ‘advertisers or partners who provide content to our Website’ for the purposes
of the last paragraph of this Section 5.
6.      DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION
We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries,
our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in the UK Companies Act 2006.
We may share your information with selected third parties including but not limited to:
    Suppliers, Introducers, business partners, agents and sub-contractors for the performance of any
    contract we enter into with them or you, including for (but not limited to) the following purposes: (i)
    assisting us to administer and support your customer account with us; (ii) assisting us to
    communicate with you about your account and your account functionality and tools; (iii) assisting us
    to market and/or promote services to you.
    Selected third parties to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us
    or which we or they feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such
    purposes.
    Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you
    and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we
    may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that
    500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use
    such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for
    example, women in SW1). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to
    enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target
    audience.
    Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.
    the Financial Conduct Authority and analogous and other applicable regulatory or governmental
    authorities upon their reasonable request; such third parties as we deem reasonably necessary in
    order to prevent crime; and other selected third parties where we are required to do so as a matter of
    applicable law.
    Credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of
    us entering into a contract with you, and to fraud prevention agencies in order to conduct appropriate
    anti-fraud checks, each of which may keep a record of that information.
We may disclose your personal information to third parties:
                                                                                                          4

    In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal
    data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
    If LMAX Ltd or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data
    held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
    If you are introduced to us by an Introducer, we may disclose your personal data to such Introducer.
    If we instruct specialist advisers (such as research providers), if we instruct such specialist providers
    to provide us with specialist services.
    If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal
    obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Customer Agreement and other agreements; or to
    protect the rights, property, or safety of LMAX Ltd, members of our group, our customers, or others.
    This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of
    fraud prevention and detection, and credit risk reduction, or with regulatory or governmental
    authorities or a court of law or tribunal.
7.       YOUR RIGHT OF ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA
The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised
in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in
providing you with details of the information we hold about you.
8.       YOUR OTHER RIGHTS
You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually
inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to
disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent
such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also
exercise the right at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided below.
Our Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks,
advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites
have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.
Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.
9.       CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY
Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on our Website. This policy
was last updated on 3 December 2013. Please check our Website frequently to see any updates or
changes to our Privacy Policy.
10.      CONTACT
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed
to:
Email                     info@LMAX.com
                                                                                                            5

Telephone + 44 203 192 2555
Address   LMAX Limited
          Yellow Building
          1A Nicholas Road
          London
          W11 4AN
                            6
